<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="/blog/tag/getting-started/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2021-02-08T10:23:30+00:00</updated>
  <id>/blog/tag/getting-started/feed.xml</id>

  
  
  

  
    <title type="html">Blog | </title>
  

  
    <subtitle>A new beginning...</subtitle>
  

  

  
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
  

  
  

  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">The Security Rabbit Hole - A Blog for Noobs</title>
      <link href="/blog/A-blog-for-noobs" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Security Rabbit Hole  - A Blog for Noobs" />
      <published>2021-02-06T06:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2021-02-06T06:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/A-blog-for-noobs</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/A-blog-for-noobs">&lt;p&gt;The section will cover a high overview of Information Technology (IT) split into 3 different categories and where Security fits best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;orderedlist&quot;&gt;The three differentiating categories within IT are:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardware &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Although a lot of future blog post will cover thing in the Software and User Domain, it’s good to know how these categories fit together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/it_hardware.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hardware Domain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading5&quot;&gt;Hardware Domain&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware domain consist of physical components that make up items for use within IT.
An example if a physical hardware is something that can be physically touched, held, moved.
A mobile phone, computer chip, computer resistors or similar motherboard components, keyboard &amp; mouse, routers, and printers are all examples of physical components that can be physically touched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;Hardware Jobs or commons&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typical easy jobs to obtain with little experience in IT relate to Helpdesk Support, but help desk is not limited to one domain.  Some Helpdesk support encompasses all three domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helpdesk Support - Fixing hardware related issues likewhen a computer won’t turn on.&lt;/p&gt;
Fixing

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/it_hardware_jobs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hardware Jobs&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;Personal example of Hardware space&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a time when an LED light stopped working. The issue was a wire connection from the LED light to the battery power source, the wire had been snapped off.  Fixing it was as simple as connecting the wire and power box together, but it required some soldering.  So, working my magic I was able to solder the wire to the power source and voila, the LED light works again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/it_software_coding.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Software Domain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading5&quot;&gt;Software Domain&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software domain usually involves developing code or making changes to a device (system or software).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An extreme example would be developing an application for a mobile phone or Operating System.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A less extreme example is making a change to a firewall (local system or network firewall) where the firewall has a change in the behavior.  Let’s say, something as easy as blocking a website or allowing an application to communicate on a port not previously allowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the space where code is created r changed.
Some other examples of code development/change listed below.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3 id=&quot;orderedlist&quot;&gt;Software Application:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adobe Photoshop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Next “Among Us” game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coding in general; C++, Java, Python, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;orderedlist&quot;&gt;Software Administration:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Firmware&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer Operating System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System Policy Changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;System configurations &amp; Behavior&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;Software Jobs or commons&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programmer – Codes all day; and nights, and weekends, and holidays, also coding in dreams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web Developer – Makes websites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyst – Analyzes data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From experience the Cyber Security umbrella best fits into the system administrations, and that fits in the Software domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;Personal example of Software space&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was able to configure my printer to work correctly without fail; let me tell you that’s an achievement of its own.  I could finally print from home, no longer driving to school for a simple print job.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/it_user_app.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;User Domain&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading2&quot;&gt;User Domain&lt;/h5&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is where all the fun is, the usage of software; applications, website, streaming, twitter, and Instagram.  In general, it’s the usage of an application without changing the behavior of a device or system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An extreme example, using software to calculate coordinates to launch a space ship to the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A less extreme, using software to design a spaceship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, a lesser example, using the recording software on a mobile phone to record the space ship launch and edit video for Instagram posting.  Give me those like!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading6&quot;&gt;User Jobs or common&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Photographer – Uses apps to upload pictures to Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading2&quot;&gt;Personal example of User space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before Covid, little things outdoor photography were a joy. Mostly pictures involved taking pictures of landscape or background scenery (Cherry Blossom, Festivals, and Special Events).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading5&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h5&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Hardware is the laptop with no operating system installed; and no apps installed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is the operating system and any apps installed on the laptop. This can include software to enable use of wi-fi, sound, graphics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User space is usage of an applications(app), web-browser, Instagram, Netflix, email, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;assets/images/it_category_list.png&quot; alt=&quot;IT Categories List&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Tomato</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">The section will cover a high overview of Information Technology (IT) split into 3 different categories and where Security fits best.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Welcome to the swordph1sh blog</title>
      <link href="/blog/welcome" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to the swordph1sh blog" />
      <published>2020-02-22T10:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2020-02-22T10:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>/blog/welcome</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="/blog/welcome">&lt;p&gt;Hey! Welcome to a new blog :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;orderedlist&quot;&gt;Slow work in progress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking for topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme ideas&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;New pics for topics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing pics for blog theme&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name>Tomato</name>
        
        
      </author>

      

      
        <category term="Getting started" />
      

      
        <summary type="html">Hey! Welcome to a new blog :)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
